## **VEERVIJAYSINH RANA**

## REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Skilled React Native Developer with 5+ years of experience in creating mobile applications utilizing React Native. Proven success developing robust and user-friendly apps for IOS/Android, optimizing performance, and managing the entire development cycle from concept to delivery.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Sr. React Native Developer (Team Lead) WovVtech | Jan 2022 - present

- Work As Team Lead and provides guidance to a working group
- Responsible for taking daily Scrum calls & provide help to solve team's project issues
- Responsible for adding Chat and Push notifications features in two different applications.
- Deployed three application on AppStore/Google Play.
- APPSCoT <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.AppSCot92">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.AppSCot92</a>
- Nexus One <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?</a> id=com.nexusmalls.elantenexusone
- HP Saksham <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hp.saksham">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hp.saksham</a>

## Sr. React Native Developer

## I-Pangram Digital Services LLP | July 2021 - Dec 2021

- Work across disciplines with team members representing a product, design, web development, and product marketing
- Testing all applications against software and hardware versions. Provide timely turnaround and documentation of bug fixes during the test cycle
- Integrated Multiple React Native Modules like react-navigation, react-native-firebase, react-native-iap, MongoDB, SQLite, and react-redux.
- Knowledge of security and identity management solutions such as OAuth, certificates, and encryption.
- Third-Party Tools Integration: Pub nub, Google Fit, Health-kit, Google Maps, Firebase Services, AWS Services, Google Cloud Services, Third Party API's.
- Responsible for attending meetings & providing a timely updates to client.
- ResQR <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.resqr">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.resqr</a>

## React Native Developer

## Kalyani Studio Pvt Ltd | Dec 2016 - June 2021

- Introduced agile methodologies and effective development best practices to division to enhance product development.
- Developed & Published Gativan Android Native App on Play Store/AppStore.
- In App Subscription integration with RevenueCat
- Set up of Different AWS Services like: DynamoDB, Cognito, S3, Amplify, Identity and Access Management (IAM), Website deployment through AWS.
- Ability to develop modular, reusable components in Javascript/Typescript.
- Design and implement new features, create UI, debugging.
- Gativan <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?</a> id=com.KStudio.Gativan
- Developed website using ReactJs <a href="https://www.gativan.in/">https://www.gativan.in/</a>

#### EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

## <u>Gujarat Technological University, Ahmedbabd, Gujarat</u> Bachelor of Engineering | May 2016

### **CONTACT ME AT**

- 77 HIGHGATE DR STONY CREEK, ON, L8J0C2
- virajrana123@gmail.com
- in @veervijaysinhrana
- +1(289) 439-7949
- 03/08/1994

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

- Product development
- Software Development
- Amazon Web Services(AWS)
   Integration
- Javascript/Typescript
- API design knowledge
- Agile Methodology
- Project coordination
- React Native proficiency
- ReactJs proficiency
- Data visualizations
- Requirements gathering
- MongoDB
- Jest testing

### SOFT SKILLS

- Visual Studio Code
- X C o d e
- Android Studio
- FireBaseCloud
- PlayStore
- AppStore
- AWS Cloud
- Microsoft OfficeSuite
- GitHub, GitLab

### AWARDS RECEIVED

Rising Star of the Year, Kalyani Studio (2020)